Laura Aydelotte

Phone: (714) 658-3827 | Email: <u>laurathecoder@gmail.com</u> | Huntington Beach, CA LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/laura-aydelotte</u> | Github: <u>https://github.com/LauraAy</u>

Portfolio: http://lauraaydelotte.com

Summary

Experienced Project Manager, Digital Asset Management Specialist and Full Stack Web Developer. From communicating with stakeholders to coding full stack applications, I bring both the technical and communication skills needed to make digital and data driven projects a success.

Experience

Project Manager University of Pennsylvania Libraries

2014-2019

Philadelphia, PA

- Managed a cross-functional team to execute multiple projects for digitizing library resources and developing digital applications
- Made contributions to front and back-end code (20% time)
- Wrote technical requirements, and oversaw the development and implementation of metadata standards, and all aspects of data management for these projects
- Directly supervised four part-time workers
- Coordinated the work of developers, cataloging, and digitization staff to fit project workflows and timelines
- Initiated and maintained collaborative partnerships with twelve special collections libraries across the country
- Delivered lectures and other presentations
- Wrote successful grants, worked with donors, and managed long term budgets.

Digital Project Coordinator (full time consultant) Princeton University Library

July-Dec 2017

Princeton, NJ

• Produced a proposal for a Linked Open Data project based on a Princeton donor's collection of 18th century American books.

Interim Assistant Director Center for Renaissance Studies Newberry Library

2011-2012 Chicago, IL

- Co-managed a consortium of 48 Research Universities and a budget of \$250,000
- Supervised a full-time program assistant and three interns
- Organized and co-directed over 30 conferences, lectures, seminars, semester long courses, workshops, symposia, and institutes across the summer and academic year

University Lecturer University of Chicago

2007-2013

Chicago, IL

• Taught college level courses to undergraduates to first year graduates

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, SQL, Python, PHP, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS

Applications/CMS: MySQL, MongoDB, WordPress, Drupal, MS Office, Excel, Photoshop,

Access Database

Data Formats: MARC 21, Dublin Core, DCRM, EAD, TEI, RDF, RDA

Project Management Tools

Have worked with: Asana, Jira, Confluence, Trello

Grant Writing

- Principal investigator, Linked Data for Philadelphia Theater History One-year NEH Digital Humanities Advancement grant (\$75,000)
- Principal investigator, Mellon Microgrant for development of the Toolkit of Material Evidence (TOME), 2015-2016 (\$7,000)

Language Skills

- Advanced reading knowledge of French
- Advanced reading knowledge of Italian
- Basic Spanish
- Basic Latin
- Basic Anglo Saxon (Old English)

Education

Degrees:

- MLIS University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign
- PhD, Medieval and Renaissance Literature, University of Chicago
- M.A. English Literature, University of Chicago
- B.A. University of California, Santa Barbara

Certificates:

- Project Management, Calbright College (in progress)
- Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp, University of California, Irvine
- Verified Certificate for Introduction to Web Accessibility, edEx